Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Hugh P. Connell Papers, 1926-1986 and undated, bulk 1966-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Hugh P. Connell papers 1926-1986 and undated, bulk 1966-1986
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company.
9.75 linear feet Extent: 7300 Items
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Hugh P. Connell was an executive with JWT during a twenty year career in which he held positions of General Counsel, Vice President and Director of JWT, and Executive Vice President and Director of JWT's parent company, the JWT Group Inc. The Hugh P. Connell Papers cover the years 1926-1986, with the bulk of materials dating from 1966-1986, roughly the period during which Connell served in an executive capacity for the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) and the JWT Group Inc. The collection primarily consists of correspondence, memoranda, financial reports, organization charts, marketing plans, meeting agendas and presentations. Many of the materials pertain to the investments of the company, as well as employee stock ownership programs. Also includes correspondence and reports pertaining to JWT subsidiary companies, including Deltakos; Doremus & Co.; Euro Advertising; Hill & Knowlton Inc.; Lord, Geller, Federico & Einstein (LGFE); and Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB). Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00677
Language: Material in English Spanish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted.
Materials pertaining to individuals' employment are closed to non-JWT researchers for 40 years from the date of termination of the employee, or for 25 years from the date of the death of the employee, if termination date cannot be determined.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Hugh P. Connell Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1931 Born Hugh P. Connell, Bethlehem, Penn.
1953 A.B., Moravian College, Bethlehem, Penn.
1956 J.D., University of Pennsylvania
1956 Received Bar Certification in Pennsylvania
1959 Student, Academy of International Law, the Hague, Netherlands
1956-1958 Intelligence Analyst, Army Counter Intelligence Corps, Berlin
1960 LL.M., University of London
1960-1962 Lecturer in International Law, University of London
1962-1965 Legal practice, Coudert Brothers firm, New York, N.Y.
1966 General Counsel, JWT, New York, N.Y.
1967 Vice President, JWT
1972 Secretary, JWT
1973 Senior Vice President, JWT
1974 Executive Vice President and Director, JWT
1980-1986 Executive Vice President and Director, JWT Group Inc.
1980-1991 Founder and owner of Crosswoods Vineyards Inc., Stonington, Conn.
1991-2001 President, CEO and Trustee, Sea Research Foundation, Mystic Aquarium, Mystic, Conn.
2008 Mar. 16 Died, Mystic, Conn.
In addition to his work for JWT, Connell served as a Trustee and member of the Executive Committee of the National Society for the Prevention of Blindness, and as Trustee of Moravian College, the Rippowam-Cisqua School of Bedford, New York and of the Jackson Laboratory in Bar Harbor, Maine. He belonged to the American Society of Corporate Secretaries, the American Bar Association, the American Society of International Law, the Pilgrims of the United States, New York City's Union Club, and Stonington, Connecticut's Wadawanuck Club. He was also active as an airplane pilot, squash player, and watercolor painter, and raised Old English game birds.
Collection Overview
The Hugh P. Connell Papers cover the years 1926-1986, with the bulk of materials dating from 1966-1986, roughly the period during which Connell served in an executive capacity for the JWT Company and the JWT Group. The collection primarily consists of correspondence, memoranda, financial reports, organization charts, marketing plans, meeting agendas and presentations. Many of the materials pertain to the investments of the company, as well as employee stock ownership programs. Also includes significant amount of correspondence and reports pertaining to JWT subsidiary companies, including Deltakos; Doremus & Co.; Euro Advertising; Hill & Knowlton; Lord, Geller, Federico & Einstein (LGFE); and Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB); and Survival Anglia. the bulk of materials is in English; some correspondence and memoranda are in Spanish.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is arranged into five series: General Office Files; Meetings; Subsidiaries; Restricted Materials; and Oversize Materials. General Office Files include correspondence related to financial, organizational and planning aspects of JWT, with a significant portion of the files pertain to company and employee stock investment programs. Meetings contain correspondence, memoranda, agendas, minutes, reports, presentation scripts, and other documents relating to meetings of JWT committees, groups, managers and staff. Also includes files related to celebratory dinners. Subsidiaries contain contracts, monthly statements, correspondence notes, charts, minutes, and other documents pertaining to JWT's domestic and European subsidiaries. Restricted Materials includes materials containing sensitive information pertaining to individuals' employment. Oversize Materials contain large-format materials, primarily charts, removed from previous series.
Restrictions on Access: Materials pertaining to individuals' employment are closed to non-JWT researchers for 40 years from the date of termination of the employee, or for 25 years from the date of the death of the employee, if termination date cannot be determined.
Subject Headings
Connell, Hugh P., 1931-2008; J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office; Simmons Market Research Bureau; Survival Anglia Ltd; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising agencies -- United States -- Management; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Investment analysis -- United States; Subsidiaries (Corporations); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections of the J. Walter Thompson Company Archives:
Harry Clark Papers
Don Johnston Papers
Joseph O'Donnell Papers
Jack Peters Papers
Thomas Sutton Papers
Edward G. Wilson Papers
Chicago Office. Media Resources and Research Department Records
Frankfurt Office. George Black Papers
Frankfurt Office. Herbert Brungs Papers
Frankfurt Office. Peter Gilow Papers
Frankfurt Office. Burkhard Schwarz Papers
Contents of Collection
- General Office Files, 1926-1984 and undated, (7 boxes)
  Includes primarily correspondence and memoranda related to financial, organizational and planning aspects of JWT. A significant portion of the files pertain to the company's stock investments, and to employees' stock ownership programs. Includes reports by Morgan Stanley, the brokerage firm which handled many of JWT's investments. Also includes marketing plans, documentation of employees' trip expenses, descriptions of company policies, and reports on the functioning of the company. Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically. Materials containing sensitive employment information have been removed to Restricted Materials.
  - Agency Performance Evaluations, Guidelines and Format, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Board room doodles, 1982 (Box 1)
    [Includes doodles made by Connell during board meetings.]
  - Clients, 1975-1981 (Box 1)
  - Communications (internal and external), 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Compensation project, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Corporate administration, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Corporate objectives, 1976-1977, 1980-1981, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Desk book, 1980-1981, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Directors biographies, 1976-1980 (Box 1)
  - Equity project, 1973-1978 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee handbook, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Executive and operating structure, 1977 (Box 1)
    [Some items removed to Oversize Materials.]
  - Federal Trade Commission, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - General management files, 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Goals and objectives, 1978-1981 (Box 2)
  - Illegal payments, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
  - Insider information, 1974-1978 (Box 2)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1976 (Box 2)
  - International offices, miscellaneous files, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Don Johnston memos, 1976-1981 (Box 2)
  - Legal and Financial Responsibilities of Directors, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Listing applications, 1969, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Local Equity notes, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Media, 1977-1982 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, foreign interoffice, 1972-1979 (Box 2)
  - Personnel files (Box 2)
    - Benefits of a Director of a Financial Nature in Addition to Salary, undated (Box 2)
    - Chief Financial Officer search, 1980 (Box 2)
    - Employee benefits portfolio, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Executive compensation, 1975, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Executive evaluation of Hugh Connell by Don Johnston, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Financial arrangement with staff members, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Financial incentives, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Fringe benefits, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
    - International transfer policy, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Management personnel changes, 1971-1980 (Box 3)
    - Manager's Handbook of JWT Policies and Procedures, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Outside Directors search, old file, 1975-1981, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Officers, general correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
  - Offshore captive companies, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Offshore insurance, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Plans (Box 3)
    - Corporate Financial Administration Three-Year Plan, 1979-1981 (Box 3)
    - Management Incentive Plan, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Marketing Plan for 1981-1983, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Marketing Plan for 1982-1985, 1982 (Box 3)
    - Planning, 1981 (Box 3)
    - Retention and Growth Plans for Multinational Accounts, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Three-Year Plans, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
    - 1984 Plan, 1983 (Box 3)
    - 1985 Plan, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Prospectus, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Real estate (Box 4)
    - Real Estate Committee (Box 4)
      - General files, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
      - Presentation, What Do Our Employees Think of 420 Lexington Avenue?, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Cushman & Wakefield Studies, 1975-1979 (Box 4)
    - Office space market review, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Real estate project, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Real estate project presentation, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Questionnaire, 1976-1981 (Box 4)
  - Related Certificate of Incorporation of JWT, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Reports (Box 4)
    - Annual management assessments: Frankfurt, general outlook, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Communication Company performance review, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
    - Monitoring report, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Report on Organization Charting Project as a Prelude to Organization Structure Analysis, 1975 (Box 4)
    - Research as a Profit Center, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Research Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
    - Review of DRIA Program as of December 31, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Summary of Financial Operating Reviews, 1981 (Box 4)
    - Things That We Have Learned About Employee Attitude Surveys, 1981 (Box 4)
    - What Is the Proper Philosophy for the Use of Research and the Agency's Role in Providing It?, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Restructure, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Restructure, Ungroup, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Retirement resolutions, 1966 and undated (Box 4)
  - Retirement trust, 1972-1981, (1 of 2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Retirement trust, 1972-1981 (continued), ( 2 of 2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Stocks (Box 5)
    - Blue Sky, Legal Department, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Common stock, Class B Series 72 conversion, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Company stock, Legal Department, 1967-1974 (Box 5)
    - Employees stock Form 3, 1969-1971 (Box 5)
    - Employees stock, miscellaneous files, 1965-1973, (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Going Public and Eurodollar Financing, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Holding company, 1974-1979 (Box 5)
    - Merrill Lynch, investment performance analysis, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Stock Incentive Plan, 1969-1973, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Stock Incentive Plan (Box 6)
      - Europe and Asia, 1969-1972 (Box 6)
      - Name and amount offered, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Stock option agreements to 1962 (Box 6)
    - Stock options lists, 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - Morgan Stanley (Box 6)
      - Cash flow analysis, 1979-1980, (2 folders) (Box 6)
      - Memoranda, 1978-1981 (Box 6)
      - Project Communication (Box 6)
        - General, 1979 (Box 6)
        - Proposed JWT-Doremus merger, 1978 (Box 6)
      - Stock split analysis, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Norman Strouse Seminar speech, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Trip file, 1974 (Box 7)
  - U.S. Government correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - U.S. Treasury Department, Supplemental Memorandum of Taxpayer, 1926 (Box 7)
  - UniWorld Group, 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    [Includes files on minority advertising.]
  - Vouchers, 1971-1974, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    [Some items removed to Restricted Materials]
- Meetings, 1971-1981, (3 boxes) (Box 7)
  Contains correspondence, memoranda, agendas, minutes, reports, presentation scripts, and other documents relating to meetings of JWT committees, groups, managers and staff. Also includes files related to celebratory dinners. Items were arranged first alphabetically by meeting title and then by date.
  - Annual Meeting agenda, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Annual Stockholders Meetings, 1975-1981, (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - Audit Committee meetings, 1972-1974, (4 folders) (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1975, (1-2 of 12 folders) (Box 7)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1975 (continued), (3-12 of 12 folders) (Box 8)
  - Compensation Committee, 1974, (1-3 of 4 folders) (Box 8)
  - Compensation Committee, 1974 (continued), (4 of 4 folders) (Box 9)
  - Executive Committee meeting, capital investment proposals, 1981 (Box 9)
  - Hicks dinner, 1975, Dec. 15 (Box 9)
  - International Management Group Meeting attachments, 1974 Aug. (Box 9)
  - Investment Committee meeting, 1971 (Box 9)
    [Includes Audit Committee Report.]
  - Regional Directors Meetings, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
  - Retired Directors dinners, 1976-1981, (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - Retirement Trust meeting, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
  - Staff meetings, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
- Subsidiaries, 1974-1986, (8 boxes) (Box 9)
  Contains contracts, monthly statements, correspondence notes, charts, minutes, and other documents pertaining to JWT's domestic and European subsidiaries. Also includes files relating to subsidiary acquisition prospects. Subsidiaries represented include the public relations firm Hill & Knowlton (the world's largest public relations firm at the time JWT acquired it in 1980); the British production company Survival Anglia (which specialized in wildlife and environmental themes; the health care advertising house Deltakos; the Wall Street advertising house Doremus & Co.; the New York-based advertising agency Lord, Geller, Federico & Einstein (LGFE); the network of Euro Advertising (the New York anchor of which was run by LGFE); and the consumer behavior research firm Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB). Original folder titles were maintained and items were arranged alphabetically.
  - Acquisitions (Box 9)
    - General, 1978-1981, (1-3 of 4 folders) (Box 9)
    - General, 1978-1981 (continued), (4 of 4 folders) (Box 10)
    - Acquisitions Committee, 1975-1978 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee memorandum, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Profit Center Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
    - West Germany Markenplan, 1981 (Box 10)
  - America Latina, Agency acquisition plan, 1981-1983 (Box 10)
  - Atrium, targeted video from JWT-USA, organization and Marketing Plan, 1981 (Box 10)
  - Deltakos, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
  - Doremus & Co., 1976-1978, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Entertainment Group, 1978 (Box 10)
    [Includes materials related to Lansdowne.]
  - Euro Advertising (Box 10)
    - General files, 1981-85, (1 of 4 folders) (Box 10)
    - General files, 1981 (continued), (2-4 of 4 folders) (Box 11)
    - Athens, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Board meetings, 1980, 1982, (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Cash requirements, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Enterprise Advertising Associates Ltd., 1980 (Box 11)
      [Includes Annual Management Assessment and 1981 Objectives.]
    - Euro-Lansdowne merger, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Financial review, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Formal reporting requirements, 1983 (Box 11)
    - General agreement, 1979 (Box 11)
    - Investment planning report, 1981-1985 (Box 11)
    - Launch meeting, 1980 (Box 11)
    - Markenplan: Philosophy of an Advertising Agency, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Marketing plan, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Memoranda, 1979-1982 (Box 11)
    - Objectives and entry plan, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Operating review, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Paris (Box 11)
      - Euro Advertising Paris statement, 1981 (Box 11)
      - Report on Euro Advertising Paris, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Proposal, 1981 (Box 12)
    - Spain opportunities, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Hill & Knowlton (Box 12)
    - General, 1980-1982, (6 folders) (Box 12)
    - Employee Manual, 1981 (Box 12)
    - Financial Review presentation, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Materials, 1980 (Box 13)
    - Negotiations, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Project Trojan (Box 13)
      - Materials for lawyers, 1979-1980 (Box 13)
      - Presentation charts, circa 1979 (Box 13)
    - Worldwide Activities Summary Report, 1983 (Box 13)
  - JWT Group Inc. (Box 13)
    - General files, 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - Corporate Summary Book, 1982-1984, (1-3 of 4 folders) (Box 13)
    - Corporate Summary Book, 1982-1984 (continued), (4 of 4 folders) (Box 14)
    - Financial-Operational Planning Review, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Financial presentations, 1981-1982 (Box 14)
    - Target Group administration, 1984 (Box 14)
    - Financial review, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
    - Group monitoring, 1980 (Box 14)
    - October reviews, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Operating reviews, 1981-1982, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Policies and procedures, 1985-1986 (Box 14)
    - Potential stock offerings, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Presentation, 1984 Mar. 1 (Box 14)
    - Results of a survey of individual investors, of JWT Group Inc., 1984 (Box 14)
    - Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
    - Stock Incentive Plans, 1983 (Box 15)
  - JWT Western Division, 1977 (Box 15)
  - JWT Worldwide (Box 15)
    - Challenges and responses for 1976-1980, 1976 (Box 15)
    - Management meeting, 1978 Feb. 16, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Public Relations Directory, 1979 (Box 15)
    - Research Directory, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Lord, Geller, Federico & Einstein (LGFE) (Box 15)
    - General files, 1979-1982 (Box 15)
    - Financial statements, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Recapitulation of business trends, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Private versus Public, 1974-1981, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Project Mercury, 1978 (Box 15)
  - Simmons Market Research Bureau (SMRB) (Box 15)
    - General files, 1978-1982, (1-3 of 8 folders) (Box 15)
    - General files, 1978-1982 (continued), (4-8 of 8 folders) (Box 16)
    - Board meetings, 1978-1980 (Box 16)
    - Profit Sharing Plan, 1979 (Box 16)
  - Survival Anglia, Ltd., 1980-1985, (2 folders) (Box 16)
  - Thompson Recruitment Agency, 1984 (Box 16)
- Restricted Files, 1973-1976, (1 box) (Box 16)
  [Includes employee travel documents containing personal information.]
  Restrictions on Access: Materials pertaining to individuals' employment are closed to non-JWT researchers for 40 years from the date of termination of the employee, or for 25 years from the date of the death of the employee, if termination date cannot be determined.
  - General Office Files (Box 17)
    - Travel schedules, 1973-1976 (Box 17)
    - Vouchers, 1975-1976 (Box 17)
- Oversize Materials, 1933-1985 and undated, (2 boxes) (Box 17)
  Contains large-format materials, primarily charts, removed from previous series. Also includes a series of mounted pencil sketches depicting the 1965 Manager's Meeting in Milan. Items were arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - General office files (Box 18)
    - Corporate Administration Registrations Statement, 1933 (Box 18)
    - Stocks (Box 18)
      - Blue Sky, Legal Department, 1969 (Box 18)
      - Stock Incentive Plan, Europe and Asia, 1969-1972 (Box 18)
  - Subsidiaries (Box 18)
    - Survival Anglia, 1984-1985, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - General office files (Box 19)
    - Executive and Operating Structure, 1977 (Box 19)
      [Includes charts from Aug. 16, 1977 Board Meeting.]
    - Stocks (Box 19)
      - Holding Company, 1974-1979 (Box 19)
      - Stock option lists, 1972 (Box 19)
  - Meetings (Box 19)
    - Manager's meeting sketches, 1965, (2 folders) (Box 19)
  - Subsidiaries (Box 19)
    - Survival Anglia, 1984-1985 (Box 19)